<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>plot on A. Solomon Kurz</title>
    <link>/tags/plot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in plot on A. Solomon Kurz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/plot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Make model diagrams, Kruschke style</title>
      <link>/post/make-model-diagrams-kruschke-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/make-model-diagrams-kruschke-style/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr You too can make model diagrams with the tidyverse and patchwork packages. Here’s how.
 Diagrams can help us understand statistical models. I’ve been working through John Kruschke’s Doing Bayesian data analysis, Second Edition: A tutorial with R, JAGS, and Stan and translating it into brms and tidyverse-style workflow. At this point, the bulk of the work is done and you can check it out at https://bookdown.org/content/3686/. One of Kruschke’s unique contributions was the way he used diagrams to depict his statistical models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would you like all your posteriors in one plot?</title>
      <link>/post/would-you-like-all-your-posteriors-in-one-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/would-you-like-all-your-posteriors-in-one-plot/</guid>
      <description>A colleague reached out to me earlier this week with a plotting question. They had fit a series of Bayesian models, all containing a common parameter of interest. They knew how to plot their focal parameter one model at a time, but were stumped on how to combine the plots across models into a seamless whole. It reminded me a bit of this gif
which I originally got from Jenny Bryan’s great talk, Behind every great plot there’s a great deal of wrangling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make rotated Gaussians, Kruschke style</title>
      <link>/post/make-rotated-gaussians-kruschke-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/make-rotated-gaussians-kruschke-style/</guid>
      <description>[edited Dec 23, 2018]
tl;dr You too can make sideways Gaussian density curves within the tidyverse. Here’s how.
 Here’s the deal: I like making pictures. Over the past several months, I’ve been slowly chipping away at John Kruschke’s Doing Bayesian data analysis, Second Edition: A tutorial with R, JAGS, and Stan. Kruschke has a unique plotting style. One of the quirks is once in a while he likes to express the results of his analyses in plots where he shows the data alongside density curves of the model-implied data-generating distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>