<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>multilevel on A. Solomon Kurz</title>
    <link>/tags/multilevel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in multilevel on A. Solomon Kurz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/multilevel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-varying covariates in longitudinal multilevel models contain state- and trait-level information: This includes binary variables, too</title>
      <link>/post/time-varying-covariates-in-longitudinal-multilevel-models-contain-state-and-trait-level-information-this-includes-binary-variables-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/time-varying-covariates-in-longitudinal-multilevel-models-contain-state-and-trait-level-information-this-includes-binary-variables-too/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr When you have a time-varying covariate you’d like to add to a multilevel growth model, it’s important to break that variable into two. One part of the variable will account for within-person variation. The other part will account for between person variation. Keep reading to learn how you might do so when your time-varying covariate is binary.
 I assume things. For this post, I’m presuming you are familiar with longitudinal multilevel models and vaguely familiar with the basic differences between frequentist and Bayesian statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stein’s Paradox and What Partial Pooling Can Do For You</title>
      <link>/post/stein-s-paradox-and-what-partial-pooling-can-do-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stein-s-paradox-and-what-partial-pooling-can-do-for-you/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr  Sometimes a mathematical result is strikingly contrary to generally held belief even though an obviously valid proof is given. Charles Stein of Stanford University discovered such a paradox in statistics in 1995. His result undermined a century and a half of work on estimation theory. (Efron &amp;amp; Morris, 1977, p. 119)
 The James-Stein estimator leads to better predictions than simple means. Though I don’t recommend you actually use the James-Stein estimator in applied research, understanding why it works might help clarify why it’s time social scientists consider defaulting to multilevel models for their work-a-day projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>