<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tidyverse on A. Solomon Kurz</title>
    <link>/tags/tidyverse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tidyverse on A. Solomon Kurz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tidyverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian power analysis: Part III.a. Counts are special.</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-iii-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-iii-a/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.0.0  tl;dr So far we’ve covered Bayesian power simulations from both a null hypothesis orientation (see part I) and a parameter width perspective (see part II). In both instances, we kept things simple and stayed with Gaussian (i.e., normally distributed) data. But not all data follow that form, so it might do us well to expand our skill set a bit. In the next few posts, we’ll cover how we might perform power simulations with other kinds of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian power analysis: Part II. Some might prefer precision to power</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.0.0  tl;dr When researchers decide on a sample size for an upcoming project, there are more things to consider than null-hypothesis-oriented power. Bayesian researchers might like to frame their concerns in terms of precision. Stick around to learn what and how.
 Are Bayesians doomed to refer to \(H_0\) 1 with sample-size planning? If you read my last post, you may have found yourself thinking: Sure, last time you avoided computing \(p\)-values with your 95% Bayesian credible intervals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bookdown, My Process</title>
      <link>/post/how-bookdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-bookdown/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr I just self-published a book-length version of my project Statistical Rethinking with brms, ggplot2, and the tidyverse. By using Yihui Xie’s bookdown package, I was able to do it for free. If you’ve never heard of it, bookdown enables R users to write books and other long-form articles with R Markdown. You can save your bookdown products in a variety of formats (e.g., PDF, HTML) and publish them in several ways, too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>