<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tidyverse on A. Solomon Kurz</title>
    <link>/tags/tidyverse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tidyverse on A. Solomon Kurz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tidyverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Make model diagrams, Kruschke style</title>
      <link>/post/make-model-diagrams-kruschke-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/make-model-diagrams-kruschke-style/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr You too can make model diagrams with the tidyverse and patchwork packages. Here’s how.
 Diagrams can help us understand statistical models. I’ve been working through John Kruschke’s Doing Bayesian data analysis, Second Edition: A tutorial with R, JAGS, and Stan and translating it into brms and tidyverse-style workflow. At this point, the bulk of the work is done and you can check it out at https://bookdown.org/content/3686/. One of Kruschke’s unique contributions was the way he used diagrams to depict his statistical models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian power analysis: Part III.b. What about 0/1 data?</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-iii-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-iii-b/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.0.0 In the last post, we covered how the Poisson distribution is handy for modeling count data. Binary data are even weirder than counts. They typically only take on two values: 0 and 1. Sometimes 0 is a stand-in for “no” and 1 for “yes” (e.g., Are you an expert in Bayesian power analysis? For me that would be 0). You can also have data of this kind if you asked people whether they’d like to choose option A or B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian power analysis: Part III.a. Counts are special.</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-iii-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-iii-a/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.0.0  tl;dr So far we’ve covered Bayesian power simulations from both a null hypothesis orientation (see part I) and a parameter width perspective (see part II). In both instances, we kept things simple and stayed with Gaussian (i.e., normally distributed) data. But not all data follow that form, so it might do us well to expand our skill set a bit. In the next few posts, we’ll cover how we might perform power simulations with other kinds of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian power analysis: Part II. Some might prefer precision to power</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.0.1  tl;dr When researchers decide on a sample size for an upcoming project, there are more things to consider than null-hypothesis-oriented power. Bayesian researchers might like to frame their concerns in terms of precision. Stick around to learn what and how.
 Are Bayesians doomed to refer to \(H_0\)1 with sample-size planning? If you read the first post in this series (click here for a refresher), you may have found yourself thinking: Sure, last time you avoided computing \(p\)-values with your 95% Bayesian credible intervals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian power analysis: Part I. Prepare to reject $H_0$ with simulation.</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-power-analysis-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.0.1  tl;dr If you’d like to learn how to do Bayesian power calculations using brms, stick around for this multi-part blog series. Here with part I, we’ll set the foundation.
 Power is hard, especially for Bayesians. Many journals, funding agencies, and dissertation committees require power calculations for your primary analyses. Frequentists have a variety of tools available to perform these calculations (e.g., here). Bayesians, however, have a more difficult time of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make rotated Gaussians, Kruschke style</title>
      <link>/post/make-rotated-gaussians-kruschke-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/make-rotated-gaussians-kruschke-style/</guid>
      <description>[edited Dec 23, 2018]
tl;dr You too can make sideways Gaussian density curves within the tidyverse. Here’s how.
 Here’s the deal: I like making pictures. Over the past several months, I’ve been slowly chipping away at John Kruschke’s Doing Bayesian data analysis, Second Edition: A tutorial with R, JAGS, and Stan. Kruschke has a unique plotting style. One of the quirks is once in a while he likes to express the results of his analyses in plots where he shows the data alongside density curves of the model-implied data-generating distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bookdown, My Process</title>
      <link>/post/how-bookdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-bookdown/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr I just self-published a book-length version of my project Statistical Rethinking with brms, ggplot2, and the tidyverse. By using Yihui Xie’s bookdown package, I was able to do it for free. If you’ve never heard of it, bookdown enables R users to write books and other long-form articles with R Markdown. You can save your bookdown products in a variety of formats (e.g., PDF, HTML) and publish them in several ways, too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>