<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on A. Solomon Kurz</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on A. Solomon Kurz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Linear Regression with the Robust Student’s $t$-Distribution</title>
      <link>/post/robust-linear-regression-with-the-robust-student-s-t-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/robust-linear-regression-with-the-robust-student-s-t-distribution/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this post is to demonstrate the advantages of the Student’s \(t\)-distribution for regression with outliers, particularly within a Bayesian framework.
For this project, I’m presuming you are familiar with linear regression, familiar with the basic differences between frequentist and Bayesian approaches to fitting regression models, and have a sense that the issue of outlier values is a pickle worth contending with. All code in is R, with a heavy use of the tidyverse–which you might learn a lot about here, especially chapter 5– and Paul Bürkner’s brms package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make rotated Gaussians, Kruschke style</title>
      <link>/post/make-rotated-gaussians-kruschke-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/make-rotated-gaussians-kruschke-style/</guid>
      <description>[edited Dec 23, 2018]
tl;dr You too can make sideways Gaussian density curves within the tidyverse. Here’s how.
 Here’s the deal: I like making pictures. Over the past several months, I’ve been slowly chipping away at John Kruschke’s Doing Bayesian data analysis, Second Edition: A tutorial with R, JAGS, and Stan. Kruschke has a unique plotting style. One of the quirks is once in a while he likes to express the results of his analyses in plots where he shows the data alongside density curves of the model-implied data-generating distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian meta-analysis in brms</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Preamble I released the first bookdown version of my Statistical Rethinking with brms, ggplot2, and the tidyverse project a couple weeks ago. I consider it the 0.9.0 version. I wanted a little time to step back from the project before giving it a final edit for the first major edition. I also wanted to give others a little time to take a look and suggest edits, which some thankfully have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bookdown, My Process</title>
      <link>/post/how-bookdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-bookdown/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr I just self-published a book-length version of my project Statistical Rethinking with brms, ggplot2, and the tidyverse. By using Yihui Xie’s bookdown package, I was able to do it for free. If you’ve never heard of it, bookdown enables R users to write books and other long-form articles with R Markdown. You can save your bookdown products in a variety of formats (e.g., PDF, HTML) and publish them in several ways, too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>