<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>robust on A. Solomon Kurz</title>
    <link>/tags/robust/</link>
    <description>Recent content in robust on A. Solomon Kurz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/robust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian robust correlations with brms (and why you should love Student’s $t$)</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-robust-correlations-with-brms-and-why-you-should-love-student-s-t/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-robust-correlations-with-brms-and-why-you-should-love-student-s-t/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we’ll show how Student’s \(t\)-distribution can produce better correlation estimates when your data have outliers. As is often the case, we’ll do so as Bayesians.
This post is a direct consequence of Adrian Baez-Ortega’s great blog, “Bayesian robust correlation with Stan in R (and why you should use Bayesian methods)”. Baez-Ortega worked out the approach and code for direct use with Stan computational environment. That solution is great because Stan is free, open source, and very flexible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Linear Regression with Student’s $t$-Distribution</title>
      <link>/post/robust-linear-regression-with-the-robust-student-s-t-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/robust-linear-regression-with-the-robust-student-s-t-distribution/</guid>
      <description>[edited Feb 3, 2018]
The purpose of this post is to demonstrate the advantages of the Student’s \(t\)-distribution for regression with outliers, particularly within a Bayesian framework.
I make assumptions I’m presuming you are familiar with linear regression, familiar with the basic differences between frequentist and Bayesian approaches to fitting regression models, and have a sense that the issue of outlier values is a pickle worth contending with. All code in is R, with a heavy use of the tidyverse–which you might learn a lot about here, especially chapter 5– and Paul Bürkner’s brms package.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>