<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>idiographic on A. Solomon Kurz</title>
    <link>/tags/idiographic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in idiographic on A. Solomon Kurz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/idiographic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Individuals are not small groups, II: The ecological fallacy</title>
      <link>/post/individuals-are-not-small-groups-ii-the-ecological-fallacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/individuals-are-not-small-groups-ii-the-ecological-fallacy/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr When people conclude results from group-level data will tell you about individual-level processes, they commit the ecological fallacy. This is true even of the individuals whose data contributed to those group-level results. This phenomenon can seem odd and counterintuitive. Keep reading to improve your intuition.
 We need history. The ecological fallacy is closely related to Simpson’s paradox 1. It is often attributed to sociologist William S. Robinson’s (1950) paper Ecological Correlations and the Behavior of Individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individuals are not small groups, I: Simpson&#39;s paradox</title>
      <link>/post/individuals-are-not-small-groups-i-simpson-s-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/individuals-are-not-small-groups-i-simpson-s-paradox/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr If you are under the impression group-level data and group-based data analysis will inform you about within-person processes, you would be wrong. Stick around to learn why.
 This is gonna be a long car ride. Earlier this year I published a tutorial 1 on a statistical technique that will allow you to analyze the multivariate time series data of a single individual. It’s called the dynamic p-technique. The method has been around since at least the 80s (Molenaar, 1985) and its precursors date back to at least the 40s (Cattell, Cattell, &amp;amp; Rhymer, 1947).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>